At least if you get the free health checkup done against the health insurance, then
some of your premium
amount gets compensated.  For
example, in the test that we just got done for Jyoti,
all the common and
routine tests were included.
Blood Tests Like CBC, ESR,
BSF, Lipid Profile, LFT, KFT
I was looking at policy ba a data.  According to him,
even 10% of the people do not get
their health checkup done on a
routine basis through health insurance.  Or they do
not know that you will get the hard copy of the health test
from the diagnostic centre
and the soft copy will be available from
Good Morning Everyone.  Welcome back to my
channel.  How are you guys?  I hope you will be fine.
So we are doing our usual work
and today is a very important
and special day,
yes
because today Jyoti's
blood test is going to happen,
so today we have planned Jyoti's
health checkup through her health insurance,
so we will give you complete information for that
in this vlog, if you see further,
we have scheduled the time from 9:00 to 10:00, so we will
come for home collection from 9:00 to 10:00
for sample collection
and we will tell you further
how you can apply and get free health checkup through your health insurance.   Let's
see when it takes.
So let's meet you, as soon as the
executive arrives for checkup, we will
talk to you again.
One Hour Later
Hi friends.
We have received a call from our health executive
and he is about to arrive in a short while.
So in the meantime
I thought that I should talk to you a little regarding the
health checkup we are going to do today for
Jyoti, Vishu and I have
recently got all our tests done etc.
We get routine tests done
annually or every six months.  So,
Jyoti had one child left, so we thought
why not get
this test done through our health insurance.
Many of you may
not find this video very entertaining.
But basically this is an awareness video
because according to the reports and our
data available,
very few people take health insurance in the first place.
Whereas most of the people should take health insurance
because
generally if any emergency
medical expense comes up for middle class people then 5, 10, 15 or 20
lakhs is not available to anyone.  So
in such a situation, your health insurance is very
useful to you.  So first of all,
you all should take health insurance if someone does
not have it and generally
when we take health insurance, many people
may not know that your health
insurance policy makes free health
tests available to you annually for every member and
all the insured members
and that is free of cost.
So no one does it.  I
think I was looking at policy data.
So according to them, even 10% of the people do
not get their health checkup done on a routine basis through health insurance.  Either
they do not know that we have a
free health checkup annually or
they do not get it done.  Generally, when we
take health insurance,
we pay a very heavy premium amount against it
and most of us do
not even claim it.  That
means if someone is not hospitalized then
he is not well either.  So
generally your health insurance amount
goes waste.  People
think that
against the free health checkup that you get under health insurance, at
least if you get it done then
some of your premium amount gets compensated.
So you must get
your health checkup done as per your policy.
Whatever policy you have,
your sum assured basically depends on that.
If your sum assured is Rs 5 lakh, then the
amount for your health checkup is determined accordingly.
If your minimum sum assured is Rs 10 lakh, then
according to that your limit is
how many tests you can get done.  You must get
this done and if you have not got it done then
today I will mention ICICI LBR to you in detail
again and again because
my insurance is through ICICI LBA.
But this is not a promotional video.
For example, by looking at the subscriber number
you must be knowing that this promotional
video is not there on our channel right now.
So I am saying one thing in general that you can get it done
through any health insurance.
If you have ICICI LBA then get it done
through it.  Otherwise you can get it done through someone else
also.  Every health insurance
company has different criteria
according to which they provide you free health checkup.
You can call the
customer care of your health insurance company to
find out
what are the criteria for your free health checkup
and what process you will have to follow.
Generally, if you do not make any claim against your policy for one or two years,
then you can avail this free health checkup.
Your company provides it to you.  So now as soon as the
executive comes, then we will talk to you.
A Few Moments Later [Music]
So friends, as we told you,
we had taken our health insurance through ICICI LBA.
So the option we had chosen was
for home visit that we have to
collect samples for blood
test and urine test only through home visit.  For this health
checkup, we had booked it online and had
given the time from 9:00 to 10
in the morning and [Sangeet] Bhaiya had
reached exactly between 9:00 and 10.  But
unfortunately he had a minor accident.
He had a collision with a battery rickshaw in the morning.  So he had an
injury in his leg so he
could not come up to our house.  So we made him sit down on mom and dad's
floor.  And look,
this is Mom and Dad's new machine also.
We did not even get a chance to remove them.
He has not bought a washing machine.
So we made Bhaiya sit there so that
he does not face much problem in coming up
and he sat there and collected the sample
from Jyoti.  And now Bhaiya has started acting like the
routine is proper.  He
collected the entire sample very well, smoothly,
without any hurry, properly,
like a professional.  So it was not that since it was a
home visit,
he left no stone unturned and now as usual
Jyoti's drama has started after
seeing the injection [sangeet]
and that Bhaiya was very cooperative.  [Music]
So if you also want to book this
through your health insurance, mine was through ICICI LBAD,
then let me
tell you the process.  But every health
insurance offers it.
Free health checkup for all your insured persons worth Rs.
5000 and Rs. 10,000 as per your policy.
Every health insurance
offers you free health checkup for all your insured members worth up to Rs. 5000 or up to Rs. 10,000 as per your plan.
All tests are included in this.  For
example, in the test that we just got done for Jyoti,
all the common tests
, routine tests were
included.  Blood tests like CBC,
ESR, BSF, Lipid Profile, LFT,
KFT, Thyroid, Vitamin D, Urine Routine
etc. are all included.  Now let me
tell you step by step
how you can do all this. How you
can book your health checkup through your health
policy.   First of all,
if you have an ICICI LBA
policy then call your customer care.  To
your health insurance.
Tell them that you
want to book a free health checkup under your policy.  Be sure to
ask up
to what amount this facility is available under your policy.  For example, Rs 5000 or Rs
10,000, depending on your policy, they will
also explain the process to you over the call and immediately
send an SMS to your registered mobile number containing the online URL for booking.  By
clicking on that URL and
clicking on the URL that you would have received in that SMS, you will reach the health checkup booking
website.  Here you will
get two options.  The first option would be that you can
go to any diagnostic centre given in the list and get the test done yourself.  And the
second option you will get is that you can
request for sample collection at your home itself or the
executive should visit you,
which is more convenient and
we also got it done.  So you can confirm
your booking by selecting the time [music] and date from your preferred diagnostic centre.
As
we told you, the health executive who came to our house
took blood and urine samples with utmost care and following the complete protocol.  It took only a few
minutes and the
entire process was very smooth and
we received the report within two or three days.   It
came online to our email ID.
Apart from this, there is another important information
here that the company also sends you a feedback form along with it.
So if you upload these
reports along with the form which you have received for your tests
and answer some questions,
then you also get some points in your health policy, through which you can avail further
benefits
under your health policy which is already
running policy.  You can get this health checkup done
for all the insured members under your policy.  But keep in mind
that you cannot get tests done more than the amount allotted for health checkup in your plan.  If you
wish, you can get this test done at
any diagnostic centre available in the list
or choose the home visit option.
Both these options are totally free
of cost and for this you do not have to pay any charge from your pocket.
You will get the hard copy of the test
from the diagnostic centre and the soft copy will be
sent to your email ID within 48 hours.  If you
want, you can print this report and
consult any general physician to
discuss your reports.  So
friends, I hope you
liked our awareness video.  To spread this
information to as many people as possible,
share this video a lot
and if you liked our today's video, then
like, share it and subscribe to the channel.
Thank you for watching
and stay fit and healthy.  Bye.